Finding Aid for Charles R. Jones papers, 1894-1942
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles R. Jones papers 1894-1942
Jones, Charles R. (Charles Reading), 1862-1944.
0.4 linear feet
85233 Aa 2
Prohibition Party officer; correspondence, topical files, clippings, and other related papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by the family (donor no. 6067 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Charles R. Jones was chairman of the Prohibition Party of Pennsylvania, 1897-1905; chairman of the Prohibition Party National Committee, 1905-1912; and later executive vice-president of the Business Men's Research Foundation.
The Jones collection consists of correspondence, minutes, newspaper clippings, printed materials, photographs, and a transcript of the debate between Samuel Dickie and David S. Rose, 1909. Correspondents include: Neal Dow, James H. Ferriss, Benjamin O. Flower, Anna A. Gordon, Virgil G. Hinshaw, Robert H. Patton, Charles Scanlon, George K. Turner and John G. Woolley.
Subjects:
Business Men's Research Foundation.; Dickie, Samuel, 1851-1925.; Jones, Charles R. (Charles Reading), 1862-1944.; Prohibition--United States.; Prohibition National Committee (U.S.); Rose, David S., b. 1856.; United States--Politics and government--1901-1909.; United States--Politics and government--1909-1913.; United States--Politics and government--1897-1901.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Jones, Charles R. (Charles Reading), 1862-1944.; Temperance--United States.
Contributors:
Dow, Neal, 1804-1897.; Ferriss, James H. (James Henry), 1849-1926.; Flower, B. O. (Benjamin Orange), 1858-1918.; Gordon, Anna Adams, 1853-1931.; Hinshaw, Virgil G. (Virgil Goodman), 1876-1952.; Patton, Robert H. (Robert Howard), 1860-1939.; Scanlon, Charles, 1869-1927.; Turner, George Kibbe, 1869-1952.; Woolley, John G. (John Granville), 1850-1922.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Prohibition Party files
  - Correspondence
    - 1894-1907 (Box 1)
    - 1908 (Box 1)
    - 1909-1942 (Box 1)
  - Articles by Jones, 1907 (Box 1)
  - Transcript of Debate between Samuel Dickie and David S. Rose, 1909 (Box 1)
  - American Business Men's Prohibition Foundation, 1930-1938 (Box 1)
  - Prohibition National Committee Minute Book, 1907-1908 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1899-1939 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1905-1906 (Box 1)
    - 1907-1935 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, concerning the Pennsylvania election campaign, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Notebook containing advisory boards in Michigan counties, 1920 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks (Box 1)
  - Printed material
    - 1900-1908 (Box 1)
    - 1909-1933 (Box 1)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Obituaries, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Photographs: portraits of Jones, and photo of collage portrait, probably of men and women active in the Temperance movement (Box 1)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Dow, Neal, 1804-1897.
Mar. 9, 1894
Ferriss, James H. (James Henry), 1849-1926.
Nov. 22, 1907
Flower, B. O. (Benjamin Orange), 1858-1918.
Sept. 11, 1907
Gordon, Anna Adams, 1853-1931.
Dec. 28, 1908; Jan. 20, 1927
Hinshaw, Virgil G. (Virgil Goodman), 1876-1952.
Jan. 10, 1928
Patton, Robert H. (Robert Howard), 1860-1939.
Mar. 16, 1907; Dec. 31, 1912
Scanlon, Charles, 1869-1927.
Nov. 25, 1907
Turner, George Kibbe, 1869-1952.
Nov. 27, 1907; Dec. 12, 1907; Jan. 6, 1908
Woolley, John G. (John Granville), 1850-1922.
Feb. 23, l906